Ellen L. Lutz Papers MS177
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Projects and subject files, 1976 -- 2006; 1990 -- 2005; MS177.009; 7.1 Linear Feet; 222 Digital Object(s)
  - [Bosnia election supervision and travel: Photographs] Bosnia IX - road home from Mostar, 1997; MS177.009.023.00019 (Box 23)
    - Memorial plaque marking where a young person was killed in Mostar, Bosnia, 1997-09-17; MS177.009.023.00019.00004 (Box 23)
    - Cityscape in Mostar, Bosnia, 1997-09-17; MS177.009.023.00019.00005 (Box 23)
    - The Nerevta River and surrounding landscape near Mostar, Bosnia, 1997-09-17; MS177.009.023.00019.00006 (Box 23)
    - Water-powered meat roasting spit in Mostar, Bosnia, 1997-09-17; MS177.009.023.00019.00007 (Box 23)
    - Landscape viewed from the road between Sarajevo and Mostar, Bosnia, 1997-09-17; MS177.009.023.00019.00008 (Box 23)
    - Nermin, Emina, and Ellen Lutz at Lake Boracko, near Konjic, Bosnia, 1997-09-17; MS177.009.023.00019.00009 (Box 23)
    - Landscape viewed from the road between Sarajevo and Mostar, Bosnia, 1997-09-17; MS177.009.023.00019.00010 (Box 23)
    - American election supervisors standing by a United Nations car in Sarajevo, Bosnia, 1997-09-18; MS177.009.023.00019.00011 (Box 23)
    - Ellen Lutz with another election supervisor outside the International Police Task Force headquarters in Sarajevo, Bosnia, 1997-09-18; MS177.009.023.00019.00012 (Box 23)
    - Lyn Hertig, an International Police Task Force officer, outside the IPTF headquarters in Sarajevo, Bosnia, 1997-09-18; MS177.009.023.00019.00013 (Box 23)
  - [Bosnia election supervision and travel: Photographs], 1997; MS177.009.023.00020 (Box 23)
  - Letters of recommendation: Emina / Nermin, 1997 -- 2001; MS177.009.023.00021 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia mental health projects [1 of 7], 1998; MS177.009.023.00022 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia mental health projects [2 of 7], 1998; MS177.009.023.00023 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia mental health projects [3 of 7] Conf. on Law and Mental Health, Montreal, June 1996, MS177.009.023.00024 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia mental health projects [4 of 7] In Search of a Nation: Restoring a Multiethnic Bosnia [conference], 1998; MS177.009.023.00025 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia mental health projects [5 of 7], 1997 -- 1998; MS177.009.023.00026 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia mental health projects [6 of 7], 1998; MS177.009.023.00027 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia mental health projects [7 of 7], 1997; MS177.009.023.00028 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [1 of 13], 1994 -- 1995; MS177.009.023.00029 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [2 of 13] Ken Anderson, war crimes tribunal memo, 1993; MS177.009.023.00030 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [3 of 13] War crimes tribunal statute and commentary, 1993; MS177.009.023.00031 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [4 of 13] War crimes tribunal for the former Yugoslavia, 1993; MS177.009.023.00032 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [5 of 13], 1995; MS177.009.023.00033 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [6 of 13] Karadzic indictment by W. C. Trip, 1995; MS177.009.023.00034 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [7 of 13], 1996; MS177.009.023.00035 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [8 of 13], 1993 -- 1996; MS177.009.023.00036 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [9 of 13] II.G.2 War crimes for former Yugoslavia, 1993 -- 1995; MS177.009.023.00037 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [10 of 13] Former Yugoslavia war crimes commission, 1993; MS177.009.023.00038 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [11 of 13], 1993; MS177.009.023.00039 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [12 of 13] Former Yugoslavia, 1993 -- 1996; MS177.009.023.00040 (Box 23)
  - Bosnia war crimes tribunal III [13 of 13], 1993 -- 1994; MS177.009.023.00041 (Box 23)
  - Colombia I [1 of 7], 2002; MS177.009.023.00043 (Box 23)
  - Colombia I [2 of 7], 2002; MS177.009.023.00044 (Box 23)
  - Colombia I [3 of 7], 2002; MS177.009.023.00045 (Box 23)
  - Colombia I [4 of 7], 2001 -- 2002; MS177.009.023.00046 (Box 23)
  - Colombia I [5 of 7], 1988 -- 2002; MS177.009.024.00001 (Box 24)
  - Colombia I [6 of 7], 2000 -- 2002; MS177.009.024.00002 (Box 24)
  - Colombia I [7 of 7], 2001 -- 2002; MS177.009.024.00003 (Box 24)
  - Colombia II [1 of 8], 2001 -- 2003; MS177.009.024.00004 (Box 24)
  - Colombia II [2 of 8], 2001 -- 2003; MS177.009.024.00005 (Box 24)
  - Colombia II [3 of 8], 2001; MS177.009.024.00006 (Box 24)
  - Colombia II [4 of 8], 2002 -- 2003; MS177.009.024.00007 (Box 24)
  - Colombia II [5 of 8], 2002; MS177.009.024.00008 (Box 24)
  - Colombia II [6 of 8], 2003; MS177.009.024.00009 (Box 24)
  - Colombia II [7 of 8] Colombia Conference, 2002; MS177.009.024.00010 (Box 24)
  - Colombia II [8 of 8], 2002 -- 2003; MS177.009.024.00011 (Box 24)
  - [Colombia: CHRCR conference], 2002; MS177.009.024.00012 (Box 24)
  - [Colombia: Literature regarding political violence], 1993 -- 1994; MS177.009.024.00013 (Box 24)
  - [Colombia: Literature regarding political violence], 1989 -- 1990; MS177.009.024.00014 (Box 24)
  - [Colombia] McGovern Colombia Delegation, February 2003, itinerary and briefing book, Washington office on Latin America, MS177.009.024.00015 (Box 24)
  - [Colombia: McGovern Delegation], 2003; MS177.009.024.00016 (Box 24)
  - Colombia photos, group 4, 2003; MS177.009.024.00017 (Box 24)
    - Virginia Bouvier, member of the Washington Office on Latin America's delegation to Colombia, looking at a loom in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00001 (Box 24)
    - A statue in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00002 (Box 24)
    - A clay horse planter in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00003 (Box 24)
    - The Iglesia de Nuestra Se ora de Las Aguas (Church of Our Lady of the Water) in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00004 (Box 24)
    - The Eje Ambiental (Environmental Axis) in downtown Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00005 (Box 24)
    - "En el llano" mural in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00006 (Box 24)
      Translates: "On the plain"
    - Street view of the Iglesia de Nuestra Señora de Las Aguas (Church of Our Lady of the Water) and surrounding area in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00007 (Box 24)
    - La Pola monument in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00008 (Box 24)
    - James P. McGovern (right), member of the Washington Office on Latin America's delegation to Colombia, speaking to a man in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00009 (Box 24)
    - Cindy Buhl, James P. McGovern, and Reverend Charles Currie, members of the Washington Office on Latin America's delegation to Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00010 (Box 24)
    - The Washington Office on Latin America's delegation to Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00011 (Box 24)
    - "Caja de herramientas" containing several objects, including a mirror, a mask and a candle, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00012 (Box 24)
      Translates: "Toolbox"
    - "Compromiso con cuestra ciudad" poster in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00013 (Box 24)
      Translates: "Commitment to our city"
    - A Washington Office on Latin America Colombia delegation member with a map of Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00014 (Box 24)
    - View of a neighborhood on a hillside in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00015 (Box 24)
    - View of a neighborhood in Bogota, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00016 (Box 24)
    - Children on an unpaved street in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00017 (Box 24)
    - View of houses set against a hillside in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00018 (Box 24)
    - View of houses set against a hillside in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00019 (Box 24)
    - Building in Colombia with "muerte a guerrilleros y colaboradores" and "AUC" painted in graffiti on the side, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00020 (Box 24)
      Translates: "killing guerrillas and collaborators." "AUC" likely refers to the Autodefensas Unidas de Colombia (United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia).
    - Two men working in a ditch in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00021 (Box 24)
    - View of a residential hillside in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00022 (Box 24)
    - A woman and man walking down a steep hillside in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.024.00017.00023 (Box 24)
  - Conflict and HR toolkit (AID), 2003 -- 2004; MS177.009.024.00018 (Box 24)
  - [Consultation on the right to restitution, compensation and rehabilitation, 1 of 6], 1990 -- 1992; MS177.009.024.00019 (Box 24)
  - [Consultation on the right to restitution, compensation and rehabilitation, 2 of 6], 1992 -- 1993; MS177.009.024.00020 (Box 24)
  - [Consultation on the right to restitution, compensation and rehabilitation, 3 of 6], 1992 -- 1993; MS177.009.024.00021 (Box 24)
  - [Consultation on the right to restitution, compensation and rehabilitation, 4 of 6], 1991 -- 1993; MS177.009.024.00022 (Box 24)
  - [Consultation on the right to restitution, compensation and rehabilitation, 5 of 6], 1989 -- 1993; MS177.009.024.00023 (Box 24)
  - [Consultation on the right to restitution, compensation and rehabilitation, 6 of 6], 1987 -- 1990; MS177.009.024.00024 (Box 24)
  - Contacts [1 of 5], 1994 -- 1996; MS177.009.024.00025 (Box 24)
  - Contacts [2 of 5] Mexico trip / contacts 10/01, 2001; MS177.009.024.00026 (Box 24)
  - Contacts [3 of 5], 1992 -- 1997; MS177.009.024.00027 (Box 24)
  - Contacts [4 of 5] B and L announcements sent to these lists, 1999; MS177.009.024.00028 (Box 24)
  - Contacts [5 of 5], 1994 -- 1999; MS177.009.024.00029 (Box 24)
  - [Cultural Rights], 2004; MS177.009.025.00001 (Box 25)
  - Early warning, 1997; MS177.009.025.00002 (Box 25)
  - [Human Rights and Conflict Resolution training], 2003; MS177.009.025.00003 (Box 25)
  - HR/CR Training [1 of 5]: U Mass training - HR/CR, fall 2002, MS177.009.025.00004 (Box 25)
  - HR/CR Training [2 of 5]: HR/CR curriculum, 2001 -- 2003; MS177.009.025.00005 (Box 25)
  - HR/CR Training [3 of 5]: HR/CR curriculum, 2000 -- 2003; MS177.009.025.00006 (Box 25)
  - HR/CR Training [4 of 5]: HR/CR curriculum, 2002; MS177.009.025.00007 (Box 25)
  - HR/CR Training [5 of 5]: HR/CR curriculum, 2003; MS177.009.025.00008 (Box 25)
  - HR/CR Training - American U., June 29-July 3, 2003 [1 of 3], MS177.009.025.00009 (Box 25)
  - HR/CR Training - American U., June 29-July 3, 2003 [2 of 3], MS177.009.025.00010 (Box 25)
  - HR/CR Training - American U., June 29-July 3, 2003 [3 of 3], MS177.009.025.00011 (Box 25)
  - Human Rights and Conflict Resolution training program, December 15-18, 2003, course readings, MS177.009.025.00012 (Box 25)
  - Human rights based development, 2003; MS177.009.025.00013 (Box 25)
  - Humanitarian law complaint procedures, 2001; MS177.009.025.00014 (Box 25)
  - [International Institution for Human Rights] Correspondence w/ institute, 1995; MS177.009.025.00015 (Box 25)
  - MacArthur consulting, 2003; MS177.009.025.00016 (Box 25)
  - MacArthur Foundation grant evals, 2001; MS177.009.025.00017 (Box 25)
  - Mailing lists [1 of 4]: Uruguay contacts, 1999 -- 2000; MS177.009.025.00018 (Box 25)
  - Mailing lists [2 of 4]: HRP mailing lists, 1994 -- 1995; MS177.009.025.00019 (Box 25)
  - Mailing lists [3 of 4], 1992 -- 1998; MS177.009.025.00020 (Box 25)
  - Mailing lists [4 of 4], 1996 -- 1999; MS177.009.025.00021 (Box 25)
  - Middle East Dialogue Group [1 of 4], 2002 -- 2003; MS177.009.025.00022 (Box 25)
  - Middle East Dialogue Group [2 of 4], 2002 -- 2003; MS177.009.025.00023 (Box 25)
  - Middle East Dialogue Group [3 of 4], 2001 -- 2002; MS177.009.025.00024 (Box 25)
  - Middle East Dialogue Group [4 of 4], 2003 -- 2004; MS177.009.025.00025 (Box 25)
  - [Peabody Museum], 2006; MS177.009.025.00026 (Box 25)
  - Play re: Justice, 1990; MS177.009.025.00027 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group, 1 of 4], 2004 -- 2005; MS177.009.025.00028 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group, 2 of 4], 2003 -- 2004; MS177.009.025.00029 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group, 3 of 4], 2004; MS177.009.025.00030 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group, 4 of 4], 2003; MS177.009.025.00031 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group] Milt Lauenstein Group [1 of 6], 2003; MS177.009.025.00032 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group] Milt Lauenstein Group [2 of 6], 2003; MS177.009.025.00033 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group] Milt Lauenstein Group [3 of 6], 2003; MS177.009.025.00034 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group] Milt Lauenstein Group [4 of 6], 2004; MS177.009.026.00001 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group] Milt Lauenstein Group [5 of 6], 1999 -- 2003; MS177.009.026.00002 (Box 25)
  - [Reducing Political Violence Action Group] Milt Lauenstein Group [6 of 6], 2003; MS177.009.026.00003 (Box 25)
  - Reebok - summer 2003, MS177.009.026.00004 (Box 25)
  - Francisco Romero, 1990; MS177.009.026.00005 (Box 25)
  - Soros Foundation, 1996 -- 1998; MS177.009.026.00006 (Box 25)
  - [Torture projects], 1991 -- 1992; MS177.009.026.00007 (Box 25)
  - [Torture projects]: Preventing Torture and Treating Survivors, October 24, 1993 [1 of 2], MS177.009.026.00008 (Box 25)
  - [Torture projects]: Preventing Torture and Treating Survivors, October 24, 1993 [2 of 2], MS177.009.026.00009 (Box 25)
  - [Torture projects: Treatment of Victims of Torture Conference, plenary transcripts and reports, 1 of 3], 1983; MS177.009.026.00010 (Box 25)
  - [Torture projects: Treatment of Victims of Torture Conference, plenary transcripts and reports, 2 of 3], 1983; MS177.009.026.00011 (Box 25)
  - [Torture projects: Treatment of Victims of Torture Conference, plenary transcripts and reports, 3 of 3], 1983; MS177.009.026.00012 (Box 25)
  - Torture Victim Protection Act [1 of 3], 1985 -- 1992; MS177.009.026.00013 (Box 25)
  - Torture Victim Protection Act [2 of 3], 1985 -- 1986; MS177.009.026.00014 (Box 25)
  - Torture Victim Protection Act [3 of 3], 1985 -- 1986; MS177.009.026.00015 (Box 25)
  - Trial Lawyers for Public Justice nomination, 1989; MS177.009.026.00016 (Box 25)
  - [UCLA] Misc. notes re: philosophy of H.R. from early 1980s, 1980 -- 1993; MS177.009.026.00017 (Box 25)
  - [UCLA: International Human Rights Law course], 1993; MS177.009.026.00018 (Box 25)
  - [UCLA] student evaluations, 1993; MS177.009.026.00019 (Box 25)
  - Uruguay [fellowship] - EL lecures, 1999; MS177.009.026.00020 (Box 25)
  - Uruguay [fellowship]: Papers, notes by others, 1999; MS177.009.026.00021 (Box 25)
  - [Uruguay fellowship proposal], 1999; MS177.009.026.00022 (Box 25)
  - [Yunis], 1998; MS177.009.026.00023 (Box 25)
  - American Public Health Association conference, 1993; MS177.009.026.00029 (Box 25)
  - [Bosnia election supervision and travel - OSCE smock, armband and tape], 1997-09; MS177.009.026.00030 (Box MS177 Shared 1)
  - [Colombia atlas], 2002; MS177.009.026.00031 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - [Colombia photos, group 1], 2003; MS177.009.026.00032 (Box 26)
  - [Colombia photos, group 2], 2003; MS177.009.026.00033 (Box 26)
    - People gathered around a soccer court in Barranjabermeja, Colombia, 2003-02-15; MS177.009.026.00033.00001 (Box 26)
    - Washington Office on Latin America delegates at a meeting in Barranjabermeja, Colombia, 2003-02-15; MS177.009.026.00033.00002 (Box 26)
  - [Colombia photos, group 3], 2003; MS177.009.026.00034 (Box 26)
    - Cows grazing on a hillside in Sucre, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.026.00034.00001 (Box 26)
    - Musicians and a dancer in Sucre, Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.026.00034.00002 (Box 26)
  - [Colombia photos, group 5], 2003; MS177.009.026.00035 (Box 26)
    - Ellen Lutz with a woman and baby in their home in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.026.00035.00001 (Box 26)
    - Ellen Lutz with children in Colombia, 2003-02; MS177.009.026.00035.00002 (Box 26)
  - [Schedule planners], 1976 -- 1977; MS177.009.026.00036 (Box 26)
  - [Schedule planners], 1978 -- 1979; MS177.009.043.00001 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - [Schedule planners], 1980 -- 1981; MS177.009.043.00002 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - [Schedule planner], 1982; MS177.009.043.00003 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Massachusetts bar exam, 1995; MS177.009.043.00004 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Fulbright application, 1995; MS177.009.043.00005 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
    Uruguay fellowship
  - Misc. materials regarding Uruguay Fulbright [1 of 4], 1999; MS177.009.043.00006 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Misc. materials regarding Uruguay Fulbright [2 of 4], 1999; MS177.009.043.00007 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Misc. materials regarding Uruguay Fulbright [3 of 4], 1999; MS177.009.043.00008 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Misc. materials regarding Uruguay Fulbright [4 of 4], 1999; MS177.009.043.00009 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Contacts, 1985 -- 2000; MS177.009.047.00023 (Box MS177 Shared 4)
  - [Bosnia] Lutz Rolo, 1997; MS177.009.047.00028
  - HRCR training - Bellicoso, 2003; MS177.009.047.00029
  - HRCR training - Curriculum, 2003-06; MS177.009.047.00030
  - IELPLAY.JUS, WP 5.1, Docs related to play, 1998-02-05; MS177.009.047.00031
  - Correspondence, etc., contains SOROS proposal, Talloire proposal resume, 1993 -- 2000; MS177.009.047.00032
  - 1. Americas, 2. Indivres, 1998-01-05; MS177.009.047.00033
  - 1. Causes of HR abuses, 2. Prevention 'Institut', 1994 -- 1998; MS177.009.047.00034
  - Bosnia, 1998-02-05; MS177.009.047.00035
  - Dialogue Group, 2002-11 -- 2003-07; MS177.009.047.00036
  - EL Files, 2002-09 -- 2003-07; MS177.009.047.00037
  - Fulbright.FN, WP 5.1, 1997-09-04; MS177.009.047.00038
  - HRCR Curriculum, 2003-07-10; MS177.009.047.00039
  - IELREPAR, WP 5.1, materials related to reparations paper, 1995 -- 2000; MS177.009.047.00040
  - Material for Fulbright, 1995 -- 1997; MS177.009.047.00041
  - Bosnia War Crimes Tribunal binder contents, 1996; MS177.009.048.00020 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Human Rights and Conflict Resolution training program: Training materials, 2003; MS177.009.048.00021 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Justice Cascade article, final version, 2000-12; MS177.010.047.00045
  - Torture article, AIUSA, 1998-05; MS177.010.047.00046
- Publications, presentations and conference files, 1942 -- 2009; 1985 -- 2008; MS177.010; 10.8 Linear Feet; 5 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains drafts, research material and correspondence regarding articles and books written and/or edited by Lutz, as well as lectures, conference files, and workshop and panel presentations. The material dates from 1980 through 2009, with only a small number of files dating from the 1980s. Most of the lectures and presentations were given by Lutz, but a few were by visiting scholars at Fletcher. A significant portion of this series documents research and drafts for Lutz's 2009 book, Prosecuting Heads of State. Other topics represented in the material include democracy and human rights in Latin America, human rights and conflict resolution, transitional justice, universal jurisdiction, reparations and accountability.
  This series is arranged chronologically, with publication material arranged by date of final publication. Research material arranged adjacent to the material with which it was originally located.
  - American Society of International Law, proposed panel, 'redressing past abuses of human rights' and compensation resolutions], 1988 -- 1990; MS177.010.012.00003 (Box 12)
  - ASIL paper - 1989, MS177.010.012.00004 (Box 12)
  - [1989: New Directions in Human Rights, drafts], 1988 -- 1989; MS177.010.012.00005 (Box 12)
  - [1994: 'The Marcos Human Rights Litigation: Can Justice be Achieved in US Courts for Abuses that Occurred Abroad?' drafts], 1992 -- 1994; MS177.010.012.00011 (Box 12)
  - [1994: 'The Marcos Human Rights Litigation: Can Justice be Achieved in US Courts for Abuses that Occurred Abroad?'] Boston College 3rd World Law J paper, 1992 -- 1994; MS177.010.012.00012 (Box 12)
  - UC Berkeley - New HR Ctr. kick off presentation, 1994; MS177.010.012.00014 (Box 12)
  - [Presentations and drafts regarding reparations], 1994 -- 1995; MS177.010.012.00015 (Box 12)
  - Reparations I [1 of 8], 1996 -- 1997; MS177.010.012.00016 (Box 12)
  - Reparations I [2 of 8]: Country reparations programs, 1995; MS177.010.012.00017 (Box 12)
  - Reparations I [3 of 8]: Country reparations programs: Germany, 1972; MS177.010.012.00018 (Box 12)
  - Reparations I [4 of 8]: Country reparations programs: Japanese and American, 1985 -- 1995; MS177.010.012.00019 (Box 12)
  - Reparations I [5 of 8]: Country reparations programs: Compensation for refugees, 1986; MS177.010.012.00020 (Box 12)
  - Reparations I [6 of 8]: Country reparations programs: African American reparations, 1993 -- 1994; MS177.010.012.00021 (Box 12)
  - Reparations I [7 of 8]: Country reparations programs: Gulf War, 1994 -- 1995; MS177.010.012.00022 (Box 12)
  - Reparations I [8 of 8]: Country reparations programs: Velasquez-Rodriguez, 1990 -- 1992; MS177.010.012.00023 (Box 12)
  - Reparations II [1 of 7]: Juan Mendez, 'Accountability', 1996; MS177.010.012.00024 (Box 12)
  - Reparations II [2 of 7]: Alternatives to compensation: Reparations - misc., 1990 -- 1995; MS177.010.012.00025 (Box 12)
  - Reparations II [3 of 7]: Alternatives to compensation: Van Boren study, 1990 -- 1997; MS177.010.012.00026 (Box 12)
  - Reparations II [4 of 7]: Alternatives to compensation: Joinet study re: impunity, 1994 -- 1996; MS177.010.012.00027 (Box 12)
  - Reparations II [5 of 7]: Alternatives to compensation: Reparations theory, 1970 -- 1985; MS177.010.012.00028 (Box 12)
  - Reparations II [6 of 7]: Alternatives to compensation: Christine Gray, Judicial Remedies in International Law, 1987; MS177.010.012.00029 (Box 12)
  - Reparations II [7 of 7]: Alternatives to compensation: Needs of victims of HR abuses, 1993 -- 1994; MS177.010.012.00030 (Box 12)
  - Nuremburg prosecutors conference - Boston College, 1995; MS177.010.012.00031 (Box 12)
  - AGM talk 6/95, 1995; MS177.010.012.00032 (Box 12)
  - Boston Globe op ed, 1995; MS177.010.012.00033 (Box 12)
  - Op ed re: Bosnia, 1995; MS177.010.012.00034 (Box 12)
  - [The 'Political Case Doctrine' article proposal], 1995; MS177.010.012.00035 (Box 12)
  - UN at SO: Lecture to journalists, 1995; MS177.010.012.00036 (Box 12)
  - Cambridge Forum talk 10/95, 1995; MS177.010.012.00037 (Box 12)
  - 'Taking Account of Accountability,' EL for Fletcher Forum 11/95, 1995; MS177.010.012.00038 (Box 12)
  - Ellen - 1995 material on reparations, MS177.010.012.00040 (Box 12)
    This file is related to material in Box 20, Folders 15 - 17 of the Publications, presentations and conference files series.
  - ASIL annual meeting, NGO panel, 1995; MS177.010.012.00041 (Box 12)
  - [The United Nations and NGOs: A Plea for Deregulation, draft], 1995; MS177.010.012.00042 (Box 12)
  - NGO's and international law [1 of 4], 1994 -- 1996; MS177.010.012.00043 (Box 12)
  - NGO's and international law [2 of 4], 1994 -- 1995; MS177.010.012.00044 (Box 12)
  - NGO's and international law [3 of 4], 1994 -- 1995; MS177.010.013.00001 (Box 13)
  - NGO's and international law [4 of 4], 1995; MS177.010.013.00002 (Box 13)
  - [ASIL Mexico conference] Post conference communication / follow up, 1996; MS177.010.013.00003 (Box 13)
  - [ASIL Mexico conference] ASIL Mexico meeting, correspondence among organizers, 1993 -- 1996; MS177.010.013.00004 (Box 13)
  - [ASIL Mexico conference], 1996; MS177.010.013.00005 (Box 13)
  - ASIL Mexico conference: proposed paper, 1996; MS177.010.013.00006 (Box 13)
  - ASIL Mexico conference, correspondence with panelists, 1996; MS177.010.013.00007 (Box 13)
  - EL notes re: panelists, 1995; MS177.010.013.00008 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence w/ Mariclaire Acosta, 1996; MS177.010.013.00009 (Box 13)
  - Mexico contacts and ASIL conference participants, 1992 -- 2001; MS177.010.013.00010 (Box 13)
  - [Sovereignty in Latin America], 1994 -- 1996; MS177.010.013.00011 (Box 13)